there's some new workflow that is
enabled by Cloud 3.7 that many people
didn't know yet with just one single
prompt you can get Cloud to design the
whole application's UI which you can
turn into a fully functional beautiful
application with nice UI and this is a
workflow I want to share with you today
so Cloud 3.7 has been released for a few
weeks and one of the key Improvement is
cloud 3.7 it's just insane about UI
implementations you can just give it a
random Mo complex and you'll be able to
turn into beautiful high quality UI like
that and this enables some of a new AI
coding workflow that is extremely
helpful and one my favorite is this
two-step process that can making sure
the UI output from cloud 3.7 is much
better than normal ones you would have
out of box and this is really huge
because AI coding agents like cursor and
Winger hasn't been really great at
creating UI if you want application to
looks really good the state of art
method is using existing UI component Li
like sh CN DC UI and a few others but if
you wanted to build something really
customized it normally will struggle but
as a model capabili became stronger now
it's the first time I feel like it can
produce high quality customer UI so I
will take you through step by step what
my process look like and how can you
replicate something similar for your own
dream apps but before we dive into that
cloud has been a real killer not only
for UI generation but also many other
day-to-day automations they release ton
of interesting features from projects
Integrations artifacts as well as the
latest analysis tool and sometimes even
I feel like I'm not catching up with all
the features that they have been
released so I'm always curious how does
other top AI experts fully unleash the
potential of those Cloud capabilities
that's why I want to introduce you to
this free ebook complete guide to Cloud
AI made by hopspot CMO Kip and VP
marketing Kieran if you don't know who
Kieran is he has been in AI for a long
time and Shar lots of good insights and
practical workflow for utilizing AI to
automate work and they talks through how
hops spall content team is utilizing
Cloud features like pures artifacts
analysis tool into their workflow as
well as specific prompts that got them
high quality results versus bad ones and
they showcase some of really interesting
use case for example they talk us
through how did they upload the whole
quarters marketing result CSV to cloud
and ask it to generate interactive
dashboard so that senior leaderships can
just come and dig into Data themselves
in my favorite section is where they
demonstrate a Content optimization
system that they build upon cloud from
how they go from SEO enhancement to
cross Channel adoption performance
tracking and content repurposing so I
highly recommend you take a look at this
to either discover all the tricks and
tips or a sneak peck of how top AI
experts are Implement those AI workflow
in Cloud so that it might Inspire some
new business ideas for you I have put a
link in the description below for you to
download this ebook for free and now
let's get back to how can we get get
Cloud 3.7 to build application that has
beautiful UI so I'm going to open cursor
and give it prompt UI senior front end
developers and specify very specific
design style that I want and this prompt
I have tested and works pretty well as
well as some technical specifications
like each page should be in this
specific size and icons which should use
online Vector icon Library the image
must be sourced from open source image
websites the sty should be telling and
never give it task this AI caty
calculator app where users can take a
picture of food and Auto extract
nutrition and similat the prodct
manager's detail functional and
information architecture design follow
the design style and technical
specifications to generate a a complete
UI design plan and create ui. HTML file
that contain all the pages that display
in a horizontal layout and generate the
first two pages first so with just
prompt itself it can already generate
really gorgeous UI outbox with
interaction animation as well but what
you can also do is give it some image
reference example in our case I can just
take a screenshot of the Cal AI app and
come back to cursor paste this image and
click Send great so if we open this you
can see that this UI looks pretty
awesome very likely you might need to
try a few different times uh like for me
I tried actually a few different times
each time some I didn't look right and I
would either just ask it to run again or
give some promp to adjust a style but if
you want to make some a specific
adjustment I can also take screenshot of
this part
and come back saying the 1250 calories
left Tex is not vertically Center align
help me fix it and make it look more
balanced cool and you can see it made
some updates and now it looks more
balanced for the tax above same thing
we're also going to update the next page
as well so I'll just come back and take
a screenshot of the original mup and the
past in help me update the second screen
based on the mo up so
great now you can see that this two page
all looks pretty decent and awesome so I
can just tell it great UI looks awesome
don't change UI just add some
interaction
animations and now it will have some
kind of hover interactions when you
hover those buttons which looks pretty
nice once it's done I can also ask you
to continue with more pages great those
two pages looks awesome keep the same
quality and continue creating more pages
of the
app and I just do the same thing updated
page or page uh like this one the
spacing looks a bit off and I will take
a screenshot and tell it the spacing
looks a bit off Place update cool so
after a few prompts I got this UI that
looks pretty awesome and you can obvious
continue going to create more page and
Flash out the whole application but now
it is still just a static page how can
we turn this into a proper web app so
what I'll do here is that I will give a
prompt if I want to turn this into a
proper nextjs web app what UI components
should I create don't generate files yet
just think and plan for now and just
focus on minimum amount of UI
components and here you go it start
defining the list of components and this
step is actually pretty critical I found
when I ask it to just go create app it
often failed to replicate a similar UI
but once you ask it to break down
specific components then it becomes a
bit easier for them and next what I do
is I will try to set up a project and
I'm just going to use chass and command
line which comes with is Tailwind on the
nextjs and meanwhile I'm going to copy
this text and save it into plan. MD so
that we can have a reference about the
component that it's supposed to create
so I give prom great I move the plan to
plan. MD I've set up in next ja project
in my app folder now let's build the
first components of app layout and
Screen layout which is first few
components but making sure read the
nextjs project structure to make sure
things are in the right place and after
Implement each component add a check
mark in plan uh so we can keep track
about what's
left and this process will take a while
you kind of just need to wait and
see cool and now if I open it you can
see that it had turned this into a web
application and everything looks exactly
like what we have before and all we need
to do just ask you to do step by step so
I just continue prompt it great now
let's do the bot navigation bar and
header in navigation folder
and again I will just continue ask it to
do more
components cool so now you can see a
check out all the pages that is supposed
to create and if I switch to the nextjs
app you can see that this app looks
exactly like the UI we have before you
can change number here you also have
analytics page as well as setting page
and each component is fully functional
all you need to do just start building
backend function so this example of how
can you create v0 level UI without v0
which means you don't have to be limited
by chass CN components you can literally
ask Cloud 3.7 to create any sort of
styles you like and building your own
component Library if you want to learn
more in depth about that specific Cloud
3.7 design process as well as a prompt
that I've been using you can join the AI
Builder Cloud community and building
where I have list out all the detailed
prompt and process plus I'm releasing
this AI coding tool called 10x coder
death for the AI Builder club members to
try free which is basic platform where
you can go and describe the project you
want to build like a not taking app you
can upload some screenshot as well and
based on that it will start generating
some cursor rules around the UI help you
break it down into specific feature that
might require to build this app as well
as design the project structure and
database schema but most importantly in
the end you will be able to export a
nextjs project that you can open in
cursor or wi surf they already have the
user authentication strip payment and
super based backand setup I will
continuously sharing more content as
well as building exclusive tools for
community members if you're interested
you can click on the link in the
description below to join the community
I hope you enjoy this video and very
keen to see what type of UI you start
building with Cloud 3.7 designers thank
you and I see you next time